# Nicholas P. Mikstas https://nmikstas.github.io/portfolio/

(408)460-2192 nmikstas@alumni.scu.edu

#### **Career Profile**

Developed strong skills in digital design and implementation for both DSP processors and FPGAs. Proved to be a trusted resource for professors and undergraduate students during a unique teacher's assistant experience at Santa Clara University. Developed an extensive background in electronic troubleshooting and repair that was an occupation in the military and civilian sectors for over 15 years. Excelled at tasks assigned and showed an ability to work with a diverse array of people.

### **Relevant Skills**

- -Three Phase Power Systems
- -High Voltage Battery Strings
- -Power Quality Metering
- -Load Banking

- -Digital and Analog
- **Electronics Troubleshooting**
- -Surface Mount and Through Hole Hand Soldering
- -UPS Startup and Commissioning
- -Embedded Systems
- -C. C++, C#, Java
- -MATLAB
- -Xilinx Design Software
- -Altera Design Software

# **Career History**

#### FPGA Design Engineer 3, L3 Communications, Feb 2018-May 2019

- Implement FPGA based modem designs in VHDL and simulate those designs in Modelsim
- Perform lab testing on products under development with signal generators, spectrum analyzers and other RF test
- Write software to automate modem test procedures using C#

## Teacher's Assistant-Electrical Engineering, Santa Clara University, Aug 2015-Dec 2017

- Taught lab classes for Intro to Logic Design, Advanced Logic Design and Computer Architecture
- Taught lecture classes for Junior Project Design and Senior Project Design
- Created design projects for juniors involving PCB design, hand soldering and enclosure design
- Guided electrical engineering seniors through their year-long senior design projects by providing technical support and progress evaluations

#### Crit. Facilities Tech., Brookfield (Contracted to Apple), Sunnyvale, CA, Jan 2015-Jun 2016

- Performed various daily checks to ensure the reliable operation at Apple critical facilities
- Installed AC electrical power circuits in both lab and office environments

#### Customer Engineer Level 4, Liebert, San Francisco Bay Area, CA, Feb 2001-Jan 2015

- Most junior Liebert associate to earn the position of project leader
- Consistently demonstrated the ability to work with both Liebert associates and customers of all personality types
- Responsible for coordinating large computer power equipment installations and startups located across the San Francisco Bay Area and other Western States, in many cases exceeding one million dollars in value to both the customer and Liebert
- In depth knowledge of three phase power equipment including rectifiers, inverters, static transfer switches, flywheels, DC power plants, and power distribution equipment

#### Active Duty Army, United States Army, Iraq, 2004–2005

642<sup>nd</sup> Aviation Support Battalion, 2 Army Commendation Medals

## Army National Guard, Atascadero, CA, 1999-2007

• 340<sup>th</sup> Forward Support Battalion

## **Education**

Certificate in Full Stack Web Development, University of Utah, Feb 2020 Masters in Electrical Engineering, Santa Clara University, Dec 2017

Graduated with Distinction, 3.8+ GPA

## Certificate in Fundamentals of Electrical Engineering, Santa Clara University, Jun 2015 Professional Certificates, University of California Santa Cruz, Extension

- VLSI Engineering, Jun 2013
- Linux Programming, Mar 2012, with Honors
- Embedded Systems, Dec 2011, with Honors

## Bachelors in Computer Science, New York Institute of Technology, Mar 2010

Graduated Summa Cum Laude, 3.9+ GPA

Associates in Physical Science, Salt Lake Community College, Aug 1998